ADRIAN SEVITZ

66 Malden Hill, KT3 4DR <u>adrian@sevitz.com</u> +44 7770 570 058

Co-founder of vzaar limited, took the company from initial concept and inception through to acquisition by DaCast Inc. Grew from zero staff and pre-revenue to 20 people, \$2.5m in revenue and profitability. Led and executed the exit process, including board and shareholder management.

A digitally native executive specialising in the shaping and delivery of technology and product to drive business. Highly experienced operating in complex technology and business environments, including management of full stack, full lifecycle technologies across all disciplines (strategy, architecture, product, development, operations, etc.)

Ex 'big 4' management consultant with experience of transforming business strategy into action; highly adept at operating in complex organisational structures and stakeholder environments to achieve the best business outcome; expert at 'making stuff happen' and taking people on the journey.

Once edited a script with Oliver Stone.

EXPERIENCE

2008 - Present vzaar limited / DaCast Inc

2019 - Present GM, London / Chief Strategy Officer, DaCast Inc

• Along with DaCast COO, leading integration effort and plans

2017 - 2019 Chief Executive Officer, vzaar limited

- Led complete company vision and strategic direction.
- Directed all activities for a \$2.5m P&L, 20 employees, and 3 countries including forecasting, budgeting, finances, legal, human resources, recruitment and facilities
- Initiated strategic plan to operate in China resulting in opening Wholly Owned Foreign Entity in Beijing.
- Planned and delivered the search for exit opportunity, engaged broker, prepared all pitch & sale assets
- Met with potential buyers, sold deal to board and shareholders, negotiated final outcome
- Executed sale process and acquisition by DaCast, including overseeing financial, legal and technical due diligence. Executed closing processes covering over 70 individuals.

2008 - 2017 Chief Technology Officer, vzaar limited

- Founded modern SaaS scalable video platform hosting millions of videos and serving billions of viewers of multiple petabytes of data
- Managed the day-to-day execution of the development plan as well as the long-term product vision.
- Recruiting and hiring of all technology, design, product and support hires, both in house and outsourced. Final interviewing with respect of all other staff (including Sales and Marketing)
- Managed day to day operations across the business.
- Maintained controlled low infrastructure costs whilst increasing usage by greater multiples.
- Managed vendor relationships.
- Worked with board on fund raising and involved in all investor pitches, raising over £5 in investment

2007 - 2008 eBay Inc, Senior Manager

- Analysed user experience across the site, presented to the business on areas which were underperforming or failing, provided actionable next steps.
- Led project and relaunched UK home page experience with new customer centric approach

1997 - 2007 Accenture, *Manager*

- Sainsburys: Drove detailed investigation into reasons behind poor performance, customer retention and churn on online shopping and delivery platform which lead to client's decision to proceed with improvement project. Lead on functional and usability design changes; Developed scope, requirements, resources and plan for implementation team
- Chellomedia: Manager of application architecture for internet video on demand platform in NL
- *Virgin Media:* Led and delivered on projects for NTL, C&W and Telewest helping to create and deploy their digital television platforms (this helped enable the merger into a single entity in 2006)

EDUCATION

1993 - 1996 University of the Witwatersrand
 B.Sc (Hons) (Eng), Electrical Engineering
 1988-1992 Wendywood High School
 Distinctions in Mathematics, Science, Accountancy

JHB, South Africa